Check this out. You're ready? How about that?
これ、聴いて。準備はいい？どう？
Hello, one two. One two. One two. That's better.
ハロー、ワンツー。ワンツー。ワンツー。そのほうがいい。
Oh, it's better? Yeah. But we don't need them.
おっ、良くなった？うん。でも、あれは要らない。
We don't need them. Wow, this is like I I've never done this before.
要らないよ。うわ、こんなの、本当に初めてだ。
Robots really realizing they can just live. I don't have a choice. It's like the Matrix. I just unplugged myself from the radio experience. And now I'm just literally in a cafe being stared at by people having a conversation.
ロボットが、自分たちもただ生きていいんだと気づき始めてる。選択肢なんてない。マトリックスみたいだ。ラジオの体験から自分でプラグを抜いて、今は文字どおりカフェで、会話している人たちに見つめられている。
This is Yeah. I mean, we've had some weird ones. This This is up for the races.
これは……うん。変な回もあったけど、これはかなり攻めてる。
We have, yeah. I I actually prefer this if that's all right.
あったね。正直、これのほうが好きだ。よければ。
I don't have a choice. No, this is better.
選択肢はない。いや、このほうがいい。
You're the guest, and you're right. Cuz also sometimes like when you're when you're I've become very aware of my own voice and how it's You're a bit late for that.
君がゲストで、君の言うとおりだ。それに、自分の声がすごく気になるようになって……それに気づくのは、ちょっと遅かったね。
How is that? I know. I know. It's like you built a career out of singing, and you're like, "Fuck, I'm really self-aware now of my voice."
どういうこと？わかる、わかる。歌でキャリアを築いておいて、「くそ、自分の声をめちゃくちゃ意識するようになった」となる。
No, but you know, actually, you know what? There is a phenomenon when you're on the mic, and you've got um you know, you got like a really high-definition microphone.
いや、でもね。マイクの前に立つと、すごく高精細なマイクだと起きる現象がある。
I'm sorry. I can't do it. I can't I'm just going to make a noise.
ごめん。できない。できない。音を出すだけにする。
Yeah. It makes you feel much more self-conscious about what you're singing and how you're articulating.
うん。何を歌っているか、どう発音しているかを、ずっと意識してしまう。
And a lot of singers actually um perform better when they're performing on a on a much lower-definition mic and maybe over a set of speakers rather than hearing it super high-def in their
実際、解像度のずっと低いマイクで、ヘッドフォンではなくスピーカー越しに歌ったほうが、うまく歌えるシンガーは多い。
in their headphones. So, as a producer, kind of one one technique you can use to get a singer sort of out of their head and performing more sort of raw and visceral is just by giving
ヘッドフォンで超高精細に聴くよりね。プロデューサーとしては、シンガーを頭の中から出して、もっと生々しく歌わせる方法のひとつが、ただ渡すことだ。
them like a handheld mic. Just to demystify it a bit.
ハンドマイクを。少し神秘性をほどくために。
Yeah, just it just it just puts the a few layers between them and the and then they can just let go.
うん。自分とのあいだに何層か挟まるだけで、力を抜ける。
Well, here's a question for you. As somebody who I mean, you're a great collaborator, but when you're making an album, you don't you can do everything yourself.
ひとつ質問がある。君は素晴らしいコラボレーターだけど、アルバムを作るときは全部自分でできる。
I mean, you know, you're comping your own vocals. Not that you're sitting there with an engineer right going, "Okay, you know, line me up."
自分でボーカルをコンピングしている。エンジニアの前に座って「はい、揃えて」とは言わない。
How do you sort of um how do do get yourself into a place where you know it's it it that you're feeling it to the point where you're going to capture it
じゃあ、ちゃんと感じているところまで自分を持っていって、それを録音として捉えられる場所には、どう入る？
especially on an album like this which is so compared to your last album, it's so about what you're saying and how you're saying it through your performance.
特に今作は前作と比べて、何を言うか、パフォーマンスでどう言うかがとても大事なアルバムだから。
Yeah. How did you prepare to to record vocals on this and get yourself there?
うん。今回のボーカルを録るために、どう準備して、そこに自分を持っていった？
Well, you know, each song is obviously different, but where it it became apparent that I was more of a main character on this record was when we actually mixed it.
曲ごとに違う。でも、自分がこのレコードの主役なんだとわかったのは、実際にミックスしたときだった。
Um and I you know, I co-mixed it with with John Castelli.
ジョン・カステリと一緒にミックスした。
Mhm. Um and John Castelli kept turning my vocals up.
うん。ジョン・カステリが、ずっと僕のボーカルを上げてくる。
Mhm. And I just initially was quite uncomfortable with it, to be honest.
うん。最初は正直、かなり居心地が悪かった。
Um and I kept sort of going back and forth between his versions and my versions with all my friends and being like, "I just I just feel like it's missing."
彼のバージョンと自分のバージョンを行ったり来たりして、友達みんなに「何かが欠けている気がする」と言っていた。
And they're all like, "No, no, no, it's way better. He's turned he now we can actually hear what you're saying."
みんな「いやいや、ずっと良い。今は何を言っているか、ちゃんと聴こえる」と。
And um and so actually the the impact of what I do like as a vocalist is often kind of uh when I'm producing I often kind of just include it as part of the instrumentation.
だから実際、ボーカリストとしての自分が与える影響を、プロデュースするときはしばしば楽器の一部として入れてしまう。
is the this is the challenge of being a producer and an artist is that you're you're you are actually producing yourself through the filter of perception, not through feeling.
プロデューサーでありアーティストである難しさは、感覚ではなく、「どう見られるか」というフィルターを通して自分をプロデュースしてしまうことだ。
You're like, "How am I going to be perceived? Maybe I need" and it's like no producer would would turn you down, James.
「どう受け取られるだろう」となる。でも、どのプロデューサーも、ジェームズ、君の声は下げない。
Exactly. No one. Except you. I think that is unfortunately the truth. It's not just confidence though, it's sometimes it's it's because I prefer the way it sits in a composition.
まさに。誰もね。自分以外は。残念だけど、それが真実だと思う。自信だけの問題ではなく、曲の中での座り方が好きなときもある。
Like I might just think, "Okay, well, I love these strings and I love these you know, this bassline. I love this."
このストリングスが好き、このベースラインが好き、これが好き、と思うことがある。
So, I'm not going to turn all that down in favor of like the lead vocal because I love what I've made.
だからリードボーカルのために、せっかく作ったそれらを全部下げるつもりはない。
And in actual fact, I sort of forget sometimes the kind of like effect that has on the listener and and if anything what separated my very early records like for example like the
実際、それが聴き手にどう作用するかを、忘れてしまうことがある。初期の作品、たとえば
self-titled and and maybe the second record from let's say like a friend to break your heart or like the those records felt more like I was part of the tapestry.
セルフタイトルや2枚目と、『Friends That Break Your Heart』のような後の作品を分けるのは、前者が、自分がタペストリーの一部だった感じがすることだ。
You know, you start the album with walkout music which is one of the most beautiful pieces of music you've ever made.
アルバムは『Walkout Music』から始まる。君が作ったなかでも、いちばん美しい曲のひとつだ。
Thank you. Um it's like so It's like a dystopian wedding dance.
ありがとう。ディストピアの結婚式のダンスみたいだ。
It's right. Yeah. First dance at like the dystopian wedding of the year.
そう。その年いちばんディストピアな結婚式の、ファーストダンス。
In my in my head it was yachty walking out of that festival and I uh I was imagining that as a sort of like You know, when
頭の中では、Yachtyがあのフェスから歩いて出てくるところで、それを想像していた。
we when I actually made it it wasn't for this album. I was thinking about it for bad cameo.
作ったときは、このアルバム用ではなかった。『Bad Cameo』用に考えていた。
Right. But it just kind of when we were There was a point in this record where the directive kind of changed.
なるほど。でも、このレコードの途中で、方向性が変わったときがあった。
Um and me and me and Jamila were talking about you know uh just influences on the record but also you know um references for how it should be and she was like look
ジャミラと、影響や、どうあるべきかの参照について話していて、彼女はこう言った。
I I don't know about all these other references like the I don't know talk talk spirit of Eden or Kid A or thriller or these perfect albums that I was thinking about.
Talk Talkの『Spirit of Eden』とか『Kid A』とか『Thriller』とか、君が考えていた完璧なアルバムの話は、よくわからない、と。
Um what's going on Marvin Gaye you know. And she's just like I think I think the coloring anything probably contains within it the answer to what you're to what you're looking for.
マーヴィン・ゲイの『What's Going On』とか。色を付けるものは何であれ、たぶん、君が探している答えをすでに含んでいる、と。
And actually it's within you and your own catalog. Um And there isn't something better than that to to to get to where I think you want to go.
答えは君自身と、君自身の作品の中にある。君が行きたい場所へ着くには、それ以上のものはない、と。
I know that was true, honestly. And That's a powerful statement. You know why? Because what it does is it forces you to take a look at yourself, probably for the first time.
正直、そのとおりだとわかった。強い言葉だ。たぶん初めて、自分自身を見つめさせるから。
It potentially to to also just to get you out of this this this thing of like how can I reach outside for validation or or or or you know
外に承認を求めにいく、「どうすれば外から確かめられるか」という状態から、抜け出すことにもなる。
for for inspiration like looking at other things that you think are perfect and going well that but it's like none of the people who made those things probably think they're perfect.
完璧だと思う他のものを見て、インスピレーションを探す。でも、それを作った人たちは、たぶん完璧だなんて思っていない。
No. Um as much as we might think they are.
うん。僕たちがどれだけそう思っていても。
I love how honest how you let people be honest with you about your music. And I like I just really appreciate the vulnerability that you that you open yourself up to.
音楽について、人に正直でいることを許す君の姿勢が好きだ。自分を開く、その脆さが本当に尊い。
I mean, I think people hear your music and probably come to the assumption that you've got it all figured out. Like who makes this record and doesn't know who they are and what they want to say.
君の音楽を聴く人は、全部わかっている人だと思いがちだ。こんなレコードを作る人が、自分が誰で、何を言いたいかわからないわけがない、と。
But every time you show up, I feel like you you you're looking for answers. You don't you're as lost as you've ever been in a great way.
でも君が現れるたびに、答えを探しているように感じる。今までと同じくらい迷っている。それが、いい意味で。
I think it I think that creatively it's like it's sort of that um you know, when when Bowie was talking about having your your feet just a few inches off the bottom of the pool.
創作というのは、ボウイが言っていた、プールの底から足が数インチ浮いている状態のようなものだと思う。
That's where you're you're at your most kind of um I don't know but that's where you want to be creatively, right?
そこがいちばん……よくわからないけれど、創作していたい場所なんだよね。
Yeah. Never fully knowing where you are. I think I think that is a a nice kind of um outlook on it. And you know, I think the album cover is the only funny part of the record.
うん。自分がどこにいるか、完全にはわからない。それはいい見方だと思う。それに、アルバムのジャケットが、レコードでいちばん面白い部分だ。
It's hilarious. Brilliant. I think you're incorporating that in the live show at some point when you come out.
最高に面白い。ライブのどこかで、それを取り入れるんだろう。
Yeah, I'll be yeah. A little supporting yourself with a plate spinning contest.
うん。皿を回しながら、少し自分を支える感じで。
Yeah, yeah. I I you know what? Actually, I did learn to spin plates when I was younger.
そう。実は若いころ、皿回しを習ったことがある。
I can tell you you're serious about it. Look at the way you're holding your hands. I mean, that's a very that's a technique right there.
本気なのがわかる。その手の持ち方。ちゃんと技法になっている。
But that Well, there was a man who came who's a professional plate spinner, which I didn't know um is a thing.
プロの皿回しの人が来た。そんな仕事があるなんて知らなかった。
So, that's not doctored? No, no, these are real plates.
じゃあ加工じゃないの？いや、本物の皿だ。
And I did a full shoot. You'll see the videos.
撮影は全部やった。動画も見られる。
I can't wait. But the um this this this album cover is my favorite album cover I've ever done. And it The reason is because it was such a perfect encapsulation of what my last couple years was like.
待ちきれない。このジャケットは、今まででいちばん好きだ。この数年の自分を、完璧に表していたから。
Let's talk about that. Yeah. Um you know, in that year the Well, so in I guess 2023, 2024, um I was you know, I was pissing off a huge amount of people.
その話をしよう。2023年、2024年、ものすごい数の人を怒らせていた。
Mhm. Um I'm like I'm lucky to be here, to be honest. Uh but you know, that's No. We I called you the day No, I mean on Earth.
うん。正直、ここにいられて幸運だ。いや、地球の上に、という意味だ。
On Earth. I do mean I do mean it.
地球の上に。本気でそう思っている。
No, I called you the day that you started to talk your talk, and we had a conversation about it. Do you remember?
君が本音を話し始めた日に、電話した。その話をしたよね。覚えている？
Yes, I do remember. like, "Go." And I really appreciated that support. I think you know, I Yeah, I am joking. I don't I don't Yeah, I do feel I do feel lucky to be having this conversation, but
覚えている。「行け」と言ってくれた。あの支えは本当にありがたかった。冗談も言っている。この会話ができているのは幸運だとも感じる。でも
I also understand that like what I was saying at the time and what I still stand by and what I'm saying now.
あのとき言っていたこと、今も守っていること、今言っていることは、自分でもわかっている。
Yeah. Um it's complex, and it and it involves kind of there's there's levels, right?
うん。複雑で、何層にもなっている。
Um uh to it, and um and the thing is you need to be able to generate a platform to be able to say those things. And I had the the privilege to say them and be okay.
ああいうことを言うには、発信できる場所を自分で作る必要がある。僕には、それを言っても大丈夫でいられる特権があった。
Mhm. Um but ultimately it came with it, you know, like after that, you do feel the tap turn off.
うん。でも結局、そのあと蛇口が閉まるのを感じる。
Mhm. Um in huge amounts of the parts of the industry.
業界のかなり多くの場所で。
Mhm. And um and so I think tangible, you really it was a real thing.
うん。だから、手に取れるほど、本当にあったことだと思う。
Oh, yeah. Yeah, when they want to turn the light off, they can turn the light off. hell.
ああ。消したいと思えば、明かりは消せる。地獄だ。
Yeah, and you can feel it. Um, Mhm.
うん、感じる。
and and I think, you know, in those two years, you know, I started managing my I left my management, I left my label, I started managing myself.
あの2年で、マネジメントを離れ、レーベルも離れ、自分でマネジメントし始めた。
Um, so I was on the phone 24/7. So, building a team, you know, starting to reassemble a team, figuring out like who I trust, who I want to be around.
四六時中、電話していた。チームを作り、組み直し、誰を信頼し、誰と一緒にいたいかを見極めて。
Let me ask you a question because sometimes the order of things is out of your it's not how you intended it.
質問させて。物事の順番は、意図したとおりにならないことがある。
Mhm. So, you say something that you feel in the moment Mhm.
うん。その瞬間に感じたことを言う。
is valid to you. Yeah. Some people get it, some people don't.
自分にとっては正しい。わかる人もいれば、わからない人もいる。
Mhm. Then you you're like, oh, now I'm I'm sort of I have to figure this out now.
うん。それから「これは今、自分で整理しなきゃ」となる。
It set off an avalanche. It sets it off, right?
雪崩を起こした。そうだよね。
It really did. So, did you have to figure out kind of what you wanted and ultimately how you wanted to move forward with your life in real time?
本当にそうだった。じゃあ、自分が何を望むか、これから人生をどう進めたいかを、リアルタイムで見極めなければならなかった？
Cuz I didn't It's not like you sat down for 6 months, figured it out, and then decided to announce it with a Tik Tok.
6ヶ月座って整理してから、TikTokで発表したわけじゃない。
No. No. So, now I got to figure this out, like, how am I going to keep doing this?
違う。だから今、これを続けていく方法を考えなきゃいけない。
And also people were asking for answers, you know, and so I was positing a question, Mhm.
それに人は答えを求めてきた。僕が置いていたのは問いであって、
not an answer. Mhm. And I was positing a a problem, Mhm.
答えではなかった。問題を提示して、
and I was diagnosing the problem and talking about it in a way that seemed to be resonating with people.
問題を診断し、人に響く話し方をしていた。
Mhm. I mean, it went so wide Mhm.
うん。あまりに広く広がって、
that suddenly I felt a responsibility to actually come up with answers. And it really, James? If you can think back on what prompted that message in the first place, what was the motivation?
急に、自分で答えを出さなければという責任を感じた。本当に、ジェームズ？あの発言のきっかけを振り返ると、動機は何だった？
What really were you trying to get to?
本当は、何にたどり着こうとしていた？
I mean, I was I was seeing with pure clarity what the kind of, um, the exploitation of the music industry in in a in a nutshell.
音楽業界の搾取が、要するにどういうものかを、とてもはっきり見ていた。
Mhm. Um, but I was seeing it through the lens of the new industry of social media being the kind of primary driver for for people's So, basically being ping-ponged around different platforms that don't
うん。でもそれは、ソーシャルメディアという新しい産業が、人を動かす主エンジンになったレンズを通して見ていた。報酬のないプラットフォームのあいだを、ピンポン球みたいに跳ね回らされる。
pay you, right? Um You feed them for free.
対価はない。無料で餌をやっている。
Yeah, we feed the platform and we give we know we get exposure and then when and the exposure apparently is enough but it's like there is no if there's no final destination where
うん。プラットフォームに餌をやって、露出はもらえる。露出があれば十分だと言われる。でも、最後に報酬がもらえる場所がなければ、
you do get paid then it doesn't matter how much exposure you get and a lot of artists are basically experiencing Okay, you you get promotion here, you get pro exposure here
露出がどれだけあっても意味がない。多くのアーティストが経験しているのは、ここでは宣伝、ここでは露出、
you get a little bit here, you get a little bit here. But it's like to what end?
ここでも少し、あそこでも少し。でも、その先は何なんだ、ということだ。
I think what artists find difficult as well as that so much of the like let's say in the run-up to promoting something, right?
アーティストがつらいのは、何かを宣伝するまでの過程の多くが、
So much of it is paid in a in advance. So, if like PR whatever it is you're you're doing is cash, right?
先払いで現金だということだ。PRにしても、何にしても。
But if you don't succeed, those people just get that cash and you get nothing. Mm. There's no kind of like my sort of proposition for the for the industry at that time was the equity side, which
成功しなければ、その人たちは現金をもらって、君は何も残らない。あのとき業界に提案していたのは、持ち分の側だった。
is which is that you know, if I do well, you do well.
僕がうまくいけば、君もうまくいく、という形。
Um and rather than being, you know they're they're they're a sort of predatory industry around artists who want to become successful just being people who just pay wages to everyone who you know,
成功したいアーティストの周りで、動画を切れる人や何かができる人に給料を払うだけの、捕食的な産業にするのではなく、
could chop a video together or do a thing like no, just give him a cut of the song. Because we should all be then working after that Invested in the right thing.
曲の分け前を渡せばいい。そのあとみんな、正しいものに賭けた状態で働ける。
to push that rock to the top of the hill rather than Mhm.
岩を丘の上まで押すために。そうでなければ、
you know, artists just being out of pocket and waiting for something to come through which it virtually never does.
アーティストは持ち出しのままで、ほとんど来ない何かを待ち続ける。
On a platform that again is just going to change overnight anyway and make it really hard for you to keep up with it.
しかもそのプラットフォームは、一夜で変わって、追いつくのをとても難しくする。
And then you know, it's like looking at Instagram promotion, you know, it's like oh, boost real it's like I mean the actual money that goes into that never comes back.
Instagramの宣伝を見ても、「ブースト」とか言って、そこに入れたお金は戻ってこない。
Like it is like every single thing whether it's like all these different platforms doing the same thing. So, the album is incredibly organic and the this um you know in terms of even just like you know, yeah
どのプラットフォームも同じことをしている。だからこのアルバムはとてもオーガニックで、ショーも、
like the show is is is me trying to I'm I'm using machines on the stage. But the the point is that obviously it centers around what I do naturally.
ステージでは機械を使っている。でも要点は、当然、僕が自然にやっていることを中心に置いていることだ。
Um and I and honestly I had Rob with me as well, who's um an amazing musician. Uh he's obviously in my band anyway. Um but we did this like two-piece thing.
正直、ロブも一緒だった。素晴らしいミュージシャンで、もともとバンドにもいる。二人組でやった。
I can't wait for people to see it.
みんなが見るのが待ちきれない。
I'm getting back to this recorded body of work. It It's kind of It's like somehow you've found a balance, a really delicate balance between the rewards of being human and why we still do it.
この録音作品の話に戻る。人間でいることの報酬と、それでもこれをやる理由とのあいだに、とても繊細なバランスを見つけたように聞こえる。
And this innate sadness of modern life and how this deep disconnection that seems to be occurring around us all the time. And the fact that we're kind of getting accustomed to it.
そして現代の生活に元からある悲しみ。周りでずっと起きている深い断絶。僕たちがそれに慣れつつあるという事実。
And I feel like to me at least listening to the album, like those are quite central themes to this record.
アルバムを聴いていると、少なくとも僕には、それがこのレコードの中心的なテーマに感じる。
They are. They are. Death of Love is uh you know, was written at a time where I could sense people's empathy for each other dwindling and it started to become very very um you know
そうだ。『Death of Love』は、人同士の共感が細っていくのを感じた時期に書いた。正直、とても怖くなり始めていた。
scary to be honest. The internet became quite a scary place.
正直、とても怖かった。インターネットがかなり怖い場所になった。
Um just in terms of where the world was going and and where I could see cuz it's like, have you ever had a conversation in real life that was ever like that?
世界がどこへ向かっているか、僕に見えていた場所という点で。現実で、あんな会話をしたことがある？
I don't know if Well, just like the kinds of conversations you see online all the time. No. Kind of angry and vitriol.
オンラインでいつも見るような会話のことだ。ない。怒りと敵意だ。
I don't I don't think like I'm not sure if I've had a conversation in such bad faith as I've seen online. Anyway, so that that song really sprung up from that.
オンラインで見るほど不誠実な会話を、現実でしたことがあるかはわからない。とにかく、あの曲はそこから生まれた。
I mean that was written about four three years ago, three four years ago.
3年か4年前に書いた。
Well, interesting. So, this was during the time when you were probably feeling most disenfranchised by it all. So, you're searching for a different kind of answer.
面白い。たぶん、すべてにいちばん疎外感を感じていた時期だ。別の種類の答えを探していた。
I think it was during it was just during the pandemic when everything just reached a sort of heated kind of Well, that's all we had, right?
パンデミックの真っ最中で、全部が熱を帯びたときだと思う。あのとき僕たちにあったのは、それだけだった。
It's the only way we're connecting. And so, we saw every side of it come out. And to your point, in the shadows where you can exercise sides of you that you just shouldn't.
つながる方法はそれしかなかった。だからあらゆる側面が出てきた。君の言うとおり、影の中で、出すべきではない自分の側面を出せてしまう。
And the algorithm is just promoting constantly rage. You know, and and and it wasn't it wasn't necessarily the fault of everybody as a collective consciousness that when something is um completely incentivizing Yeah.
アルゴリズムは、怒りを絶えず推してくる。集団としての意識で、全員のせいだったわけではない。何かを完全に促す仕組みがあると、
that type of behavior and and kind of interaction, then that's what we get. And of course it would be. So, It just went into a black hole, right?
その行動や関わり方が、僕たちが得るものになる。もちろんそうなる。ブラックホールに落ちていった。
Yeah, and I think that, you know, things like you know, the the the rest of the record though is is the whole album's not about that.
うん。ただ、レコードの残りは、アルバム全体がその話というわけではない。
It's just I I think this record is you know, to encapsulate it into maybe a phrase would be love in a time of chaos.
このレコードを一言で包むなら、「混沌の時代の愛」だ。
Mhm. And I think I want I was I was struggling to reconcile what it feels like to be someone with their own experience, with their own life, their love, their friends, their passions
うん。自分自身の経験、自分の人生、愛、友達、情熱、
their depression, their whatever it is, you know, that you're you're going through at the time. With the collective anguish and the collective experience that's going on in the world.
落ち込み、そのとき通っているものと、世界で起きている集合的な苦痛と、集合的な経験を、どう折り合わせるかに苦しんでいた。
And the things that happened over the last four years that that have been in your from from outside that you have to reconcile and say you know how how much do I interface
この4年、外から入ってきて、折り合わせなければならないこと。どれだけ関わるか。
with how much how complicit am I am I in this how much how much how much can I block off consciously and subconsciously and ethically and how much do I have to engage
どれだけ加担しているか。意識的にも、無意識にも、倫理的にも、どれだけ遮断できるか。どれだけ関わらなければならないか。
given that all of that information is being pumped directly into my hand you know what which is a not the best turn phrase maybe but um you know what I'm saying so uh
その情報が全部、手の中に直接送り込まれている。言い回しとしてはいちばんではないかもしれない。でも、言いたいことはわかると思う。
so what I'm saying is that so I'm saying is that the um that's a difficult thing to do I want to get back to the plate spinning of it all what's the how
だから言いたいのは、それは難しいということだ。皿回しの話に戻りたい。どうやって、
do you learn how to spin plates efficiently and without absolute disaster you can't constantly you can't like how many plates did you have to go through before you really felt like and eventually
効率よく、大惨事なしに皿を回せるようになる？ずっとやってはいられない。本当にできるようになるまで、何枚の皿を割った？そして結局、
also there's something very deep about this experience because no matter how successful you are the plate it's all going to end the same way that's right that is right um those plates are
この経験にはとても深いものがある。どれだけ成功しても、皿は同じ終わり方をする。そのとおりだ。
inevitably going to spin if you if you don't keep them going they're going to fall off and smash on the floor which they did there'll be a video documenting that boxes and boxes
回し続けなければ、皿は落ちて床で割れる。実際に割れた。それを記録した動画もある。箱に箱、
of plates boxes of boxes of plates yeah um and and yeah like I say like it was it was a metaphor for all these things I was doing I was I was I
皿の箱だ。うん。言ったとおり、やっていたこと全部のメタファーだった。
mean as I was getting to earlier I was I was um I was becoming an advisor to all these different companies that I felt were the sort of and I and still do
さっきの続きだけど、いろんな会社のアドバイザーになっていた。今もそう感じている。
feel like in the five vault all these things that are the to me that are the the next phase of the music industry um now that the kind of majors are finding new
Vaultをはじめ、僕にとって音楽業界の次の段階だと思えるもの全部。メジャーが新しい形を見つけて、
shapes and you know disassembling reassembling and you're getting a much more independently driven music industry which is great and that's as I said it said it would be and and I hoped it
分解して組み直し、もっとインディ主導の音楽業界になっていく。それは素晴らしい。言っていたとおりになるし、そうなることを望んでいた。
would be. um and I was also starting my own uh platform um which is I can't talk about right now but I will later.
そうなる。自分のプラットフォームも始めていた。今は話せないけれど、あとで話す。
You'll come back talk about it. Yeah. Okay.
戻ってきて話して。うん。わかった。
Yeah. Um and then you know I just um you know I was doing I I was making the album and I was trying to be a good boyfriend dog dad person trying to figure
うん。アルバムを作りながら、いい彼氏で、犬のパパで、一人の人間として、人生を見極めようとしていた。
out my life. And you moved can I say that? I mean you moved as well.
引っ越したことも言っていい？引っ越したよね。
I moved country. Yeah. Um moved home. I moved home which was which was great um but yeah. um There's probably more things I guess leaving label management managing myself.
国を移った。うん。家を移した。それは良かった。レーベルとマネジメントを離れて、自分でマネジメントしたこと以上に、たぶんまだある。
Yeah it was it was just crazy it was a crazy amount of stuff to be doing at once and it was too much honestly. um which is why we pushed the album back by a year.
うん。同時にやるには狂った量で、正直、多すぎた。だからアルバムを1年遅らせた。
um but that when I look at that to to say I was spinning plates but also sort of conducting um at the same time is what that looks like to me.
でも今振り返ると、皿を回しながら、同時に指揮もしていた。あの姿はそういうものだ。
What have you learned from um moving into these new spaces like like you've been on vault now for what a couple of years?
この新しい場所に入って、何を学んだ？Vaultには、もう2年くらいいる？
Like what have you learned about um having this kind of direct to fan engagement? Like I I was I subscribed the day you you announced it.
ファンと直接つながるこの形について、何を学んだ？発表した日に購読した。
Thank you. Of course. And I'm still a subscriber and so I I hear from you fairly regularly. I always get excited and then I realize it's not you.
ありがとう。もちろん。今も購読している。わりと定期的に君から連絡が来る。いつもワクワクして、それから君本人じゃないと気づく。
I feel like it's like it's like it's like music chemio.
音楽のケミオみたいだ。
It is me though. It's like me but it's not you.
でも僕本人ではある。僕みたいだけど、君じゃない。
you know I'm writing the text. it's the same text.
文章は僕が書いている。同じ文章だ。
You mean it's you not it's not me too directly to you.
つまり君であって、僕に直接ではないってこと？
No it's not a whenever I see James Blake come up I would like it to say hey Zane been a minute. I'm in LA next week. Fancy a pint?"
違う。James Blakeと出たら、「ようゼイン、久しぶり。来週LAにいる。一杯どう？」と言ってほしい。
But what I get is like "Hi everyone. I'm releasing a limited edition coffee mug on Monday. Would you like it?
来るのは「みなさんこんにちは。月曜に限定のコーヒーマグを出します。欲しいですか。
Um sign up here." And I go "I do want the coffee mug, but I would like to have a pint with my friend, too."
こちらから登録を」。マグは欲しい。でも友達と一杯もやりたい。
Mhm. So, I don't understand why seen that response.
うん。その返事を見られない理由がわからない。
I'm not surprised. end of Vault, but it's just why it had to be either or. I I thought that you would it would be additive. I thought I'm going to keep my friendship and get Vault.
驚かない。Vaultが終わる、というより、なぜどちらか一方でなければならなかったのか。足し算だと思っていた。友情は残して、Vaultも得るんだと。
I didn't realize when I signed up to Vault, I would be losing my friend in the process. I might have not done it.
Vaultに登録したら、その過程で友達を失うとは思っていなかった。知っていたら、やらなかったかもしれない。
But that's capitalism. Honestly. That's Wow, you really learned some How many Mhm.
それが資本主義だ。正直。すごい、よく学んだね。
Boy, they they broke you, huh? Yeah. They broke you.
まったく、壊されたね。うん。壊された。
LA just destroyed me. I have no soul anymore.
LAが僕を破壊した。もう魂がない。
Wow. It's gone. That is capitalism, you're right. It's a sacrifice and a trade.
うわ。消えた。それが資本主義だ、そのとおり。犠牲と取引だ。
But I do I appreciate your subscription. More than my friendship, clearly.
でも購読は感謝している。友情より、明らかに。
Thank you for your subscription. You know what's been great is that you know, like this week Mhm.
ご購読ありがとうございます。良かったのは、今週、
I was in LA and then we did a listening party for for the Vault members, right?
LAにいて、Vaultのメンバー向けの試聴会をやったことだ。
And we played them the album and this is and I I went and said hello to everyone and like had a big big old chat at the end and like they'd never met
アルバムをかけて、最後にみんなに挨拶して、長く話した。会ったことのない人たちで、
me before and we were doing we were just sort of like it was a great they had all these questions and Yeah.
質問もたくさんあって。うん。
And it felt very very relaxed because I've I already know half of them because we've already been chatting on this thing. And it felt very um like I've never really had that before.
とてもリラックスして感じた。この仕組みで、すでに半分の人を知っていたから。今まで本当になかった感覚だ。
Like because social media is so kind of parasocial Mhm.
ソーシャルメディアは、すごくパラソーシャルだから。
and it's and it you know, it's sort of like your Instagram is sort of like it's it's the quality of the comments is totally different, right?
Instagramは、コメントの質がまったく違う。
So, it's like you know, you might just somebody might just say like Zaddy.
誰かがただ「Zaddy」と言うかもしれない。
Mhm. Often. And I go that and I just what do I do? I respond Mhm.
うん。よくある。それで、どうすればいい？返事はする。
is that right Eddie I respond but yeah that's true am I not okay I'm not old enough no okay you're not at uncle level yet I think I might be so no okay
エディ、それで合ってる？返事はする。でも「それは本当だ。僕は大丈夫じゃない。まだその歳じゃない。おじさん枠には早い」となる。僕はもうそうかもしれない。いや、
well anyway whatever the comment is right okay so someone's I'm just going right With a goat emoji. Goat emoji.
とにかくコメントが何であれ、山羊の絵文字で返す。山羊の絵文字。
Obviously the connection is undeniable. From from that. Obviously you also an undeniably a goat.
つながりは否定できない。そこから。君も、疑いようもなく山羊だ。
I just stop it. So yes parasocial is parasocial. Zane's in the comments saying goat.
やめてくれ。そう、パラソーシャルはパラソーシャルだ。ゼインがコメントで山羊と言っている。
Goat. I I don't know what to say to be honest it's not even it's not even just that it's not anything. Like Instagram just feels like or any of those places.
山羊。正直、何と言えばいいかわからない。それだけではなく、何もない。Instagramとか、ああいう場所はただそう感じる。
It actually personalizes the most personal relationships in your life.
人生でいちばん個人的な関係まで、個人宛てみたいにしてしまう。
I have family and friends who have known me better than anybody in the world who comment on my post and I'm like what what am I what am I say to that.
世界の誰より僕を知っている家族や友達が投稿にコメントして、「これに何て返せばいいんだ」となる。
Like we're going to call him out on your Apple show. I mean that's probably the only interaction they have with you isn't it looking at your videos.
Appleの番組で名指しにするぞ。たぶん、彼らと君の接点は、動画を見ることだけなんだろう。
I'm a good friend. Sacrifice friendship for capitalism. I imagine these you know people back home God he sounds Australian. You can off. What's happening he's he's become so LA.
僕はいい友達だ。友情を資本主義に差し出した。故郷の人たちが想像できる。「神よ、オーストラリア人みたいな声だ。何が起きたんだ、すごくLAになった」。
He's so LA but his voice has changed and now he thinks he's Australian Mark Ronson no one knows where he's from. He's got these rings we don't remember that.
すごくLAなのに、声が変わって、今はオーストラリア人だと思っている。マーク・ロンソンは、出身がわからない。指輪をしている。そんなの覚えていない。
Remember We don't remember him wearing fancy jewelry.
派手なジュエリーをしていた記憶はない。
I've been to your houses. Is he does he does he still love us do you think? Have you heard from him in I haven't heard from him in 5 years.
君の家にも行った。まだ僕たちを愛していると思う？連絡は？5年も聞いていない。
These are the questions I want people to ask.
人が聞いてほしい質問は、これだ。
But he's talking also to these famous people. Is he And now he's famous like is he too big too big to come home?
でも有名人とも話している。有名になって、帰るには大きすぎる？
Is he Does he remember even where he's from? I'm sure they're all I you know, I'm sure they're not saying that.
自分がどこ出身か、まだ覚えている？みんなそう言っているに違いない。いや、言っていないと思う。
It's possible they are. I'm just want I'm just I'm just imagining.
言っている可能性はある。想像しているだけだ。
I think that all the time about you. And genuinely I'm like, wow, where the is James gone?
君のことはいつもそう思っている。本気で「ジェームズはどこへ行ったんだ」と。
He came in, swept by the industry, off, back to London, and now all I get is limited edition 7-in demo coming Thursday.
業界にさらわれて、ロンドンに戻って、今もらえるのは木曜発売の限定7インチのデモだけだ。
Um I'm just grateful we're still here and I now get to listen to this with everybody else when I need it and we need this.
まだここにいられて、必要なときに、僕たちに必要なこれを、みんなと一緒に聴けるのがただありがたい。
Mhm. Record, man. We need someone who's going to And you're not alone. Well, you've got some real generational peers right now. You know, Roses doing this.
うん。レコードだ。君は一人じゃない。今、同世代の本物の仲間がいる。ローズがこれをやっている。
Oh, yeah. Florence's album is unfucking believable. Like people need to remember that record exists right now. Cuz that is like Old Religion, that song.
ああ。フローレンスのアルバムは、信じられないくらいすごい。あのレコードが今あることを、人は思い出すべきだ。『Old Religion』、あの曲。
Mhm. I mean, there's some people who are really out here saying amazing brave, amazing So as much as it probably felt like you were on your own for a bit after, you know
うん。外に出て、勇敢で素晴らしいことを言っている人たちがいる。あのあと、しばらく一人だったように感じたとしても。
whatever that was in 2024 when you started that ball rolling.
2024年に、あの球を転がしたときのことだ。
Mhm. It must be nice to to know that actually the real ones are still here and still want to work with you. I mean, you don't have any problem finding great people to work with and continually.
本物はまだここにいて、まだ君と仕事をしたがっていると知れるのは、いいことのはずだ。素晴らしい人と働き続けるのに、困ってはいない。
No, I'm I'm super I'm incredibly lucky in that way. And also, you know, I never felt like it I was on my own same times what I was saying.
その点では、信じられないくらい幸運だ。それに、言っていたことについて、自分が一人だと感じたことはない。
Um cuz lots of people And by the way, not even 50th on the list of I I I mean I'm or I I am so far down the list of people who've said the same things.
たくさんの人がいる。ついでに言うと、同じことを言った人のリストで、僕は50番目にすら入らない。
You know, I'm I'm like there's there's so many articles, there's so many musicians who've spoken out about things in this industry and and you know
この業界について声を上げた記事も、ミュージシャンも、すごくたくさんいる。
I'm by no means the first and hopefully won't be the last, but the the in terms of music and making it um I always you know, I'm always grateful people like Rosalía exist.
僕が最初ではないし、最後でもないといい。音楽を作ることについては、ロザリアのような人がいて、いつもありがたい。
I mean, there is only one, obviously, but just watching her interviews about this last record. You can just sense the artistry sort of just pouring out of her.
もちろん一人しかいない。でも最新作についてのインタビューを見ていると、芸術性があふれ出しているのが感じられる。
I mean, it's like student, she's studying student.
学生みたいだ。研究している学生。
Yeah, it's amazing. She's amazing. I'm going to super serve my curiosity.
うん、すごい。彼女はすごい。好奇心にしっかり応えるよ。
But she's also a teacher in a way in in the way she's doing it.
でも彼女のやり方は、ある意味で教師でもある。
It's kind of it's broadcasting a sort of a frequency to other people that says you can you can do this, you can take risks, you can challenge yourself
他の人に周波数を送って、「君にもできる。リスクを取れる。自分に挑戦できる」と言っている。
you can be um and you can be truly great and you can be like one of if not the best singer on the planet and just still around and have a great time.
本当に偉大でいられる。この惑星で最高のシンガーの一人でいながら、まだここにいて、楽しめる、と。
Yeah, carry it and and and just be thoughtful and cool about it.
うん。それを背負って、思慮深く、クールでいられる。
And then go and sell out 30,000 cap like whatever or like, you know you go to a Rosalía she puts on a gig and it looks like a it looks like a national protest.
そして3万人規模を売り切る。ロザリアのライブに行くと、国民的な抗議集会みたいに見える。
Do you know what I mean? Like insane.
わかるでしょ。異常だ。
I know. I know. Um So, I know you were doing you were working with Dave on Dave's stuff and then obviously Dave's on this record, too.
わかる。デイブの作品で一緒にやっていて、当然、デイブもこのレコードにいる。
And that makes a lot of sense because again, you only really collaborate with people that that that kind of makes sense on every single level. Um but how's that experience been working with him?
それはすごく筋が通る。君は、あらゆるレベルで意味が通る人としか、本当にはコラボしない。彼と働く経験はどうだった？
Cuz I I I love him. We all love him and he's like you, he's not he's only going to move when he's ready. It's all very purposeful and deliberate and he's he's um he's a one-off.
僕は彼が大好きだ。みんな好きだ。彼は君と同じで、準備ができてからしか動かない。すべてに意図と慎重さがある。唯一無二だ。
Complete one-off. Just total um You know, when when he's been working on something and he comes back and then he shows you what he's done and he just you know, you the song's playing and
完全に唯一無二だ。彼が何かやって戻ってきて、見せてくれる。曲が流れていて、
and he's just going, "Yeah, so I've just got this thing." And and then he starts doing it. And he wraps the whole thing from start to finish and you go what?
「うん、こういうのを入れた」と言いながらやり始める。最初から最後まで一気に包んで、こっちは「何だ？」となる。
Like, how did you do that? It's completely the depth of writing from him is astonishing, I think, sometimes. I'm like, there's just the the gravity of what he says and how much thought he's put into it.
どうやったんだ。彼の書くものの深さは、ときどき驚異的だ。言葉の重力と、そこに注いだ思考の量がすごい。
And it's like that's why Dave records can't come that often. They're just you know, people are like, "Oh, come on, man.
だからデイブのレコードは、そんなに頻繁には出せない。みんな「早く出せよ」と言う。
Drop drop an album." It's like a drop. No. We're not This This is No, it's This is a This is a This is a delivery of like a Yeah.
「アルバムを落とせ」と。ドロップじゃない。これは、一夜で作れるものではない。
unbelievably special thing that that that doesn't get made in a night. When you love something a lot and it's obviously very personal to you and it is for every artist.
信じられないくらい特別なものの受け渡しだ。何かをとても愛していて、自分にとって明らかに個人的なものなら、それはすべてのアーティストにとってそうだ。
And then you you know you then are put in touch with the reality of what you're going to have to do to actually like show it to people.
それから、それを実際に人に見せるために、何をしなければならないかという現実につながる。
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Um Learn how to spin plates for a start.
うん。まず、皿の回し方を覚えることだ。
Well, it's a I mean, it's just a a deeply um impersonal and kind of like tech-driven process, right?
つまり、深く、人の温度がなく、技術に駆動されたプロセスなんだ。
So and and I think this is this is kind of what the one of the not I'd say uh amendments I made to some of the first statements I I made about the
そしてこれは、最初に言ったことへの修正のひとつだと思う。
about you know, streaming and payment and all that kind of stuff.
ストリーミングや支払い、そのあたりの話全部について。
Was that in actual fact, about a year later, I sort of came to the realization that the streaming the the delivery of music in that format might not actually be worth more money
実際には、約1年後に気づいた。あの形式で音楽を届けることには、それ以上のお金の価値はないのかもしれない、と。
than that. Cuz it's so It's It's so like compared to buying by you know
買って持ち帰ることに比べると、あまりに違うから。
like if if let's say we go like that and this kind of culture is just back to like buying vinyl and having to bring it home and Your question is are we really
文化がまた、ヴァイナルを買って家に持ち帰るほうへ戻ったとして。問いは、本当に、
going to Are we really going to put that on wax? Are we going to press that?
それをワックスに落とすのか。プレスするのか、だ。
Are we going to stand by that decision when it's actually something physical we have to go through a process as opposed to just putting it be 200 and 50 songs a day if
ただ載せるのとは違って、物理的な工程を経なければならないとき、その決断を引き受けるのか。もしプレスが必要なら、1日に250曲なんて、
it was if you had to press them to vinyl.
出さない。
undeniable And And not only that, but like And I say yes, the quality control becomes vastly less when all it is is literally upload. That's why live music is now such a sort of hot commodity in a way.
否定できない。アップロードするだけなら、品質管理は大幅に緩む。だからライブが、ある意味で、これほど熱いものになった。
Like watching someone live is is so far away from the phone and streaming. But it's not that far away from a vinyl that was pressed through an analog Do you know Do you see what I'm saying?
誰かを生で見ることは、スマホやストリーミングからとても遠い。でも、アナログを通してプレスされたヴァイナルからは、そんなに遠くない。言っていること、わかる？
Like It went straight through a tape machine onto it onto vinyl.
テープマシンをまっすぐ通って、ヴァイナルに乗った。
That actually isn't that far away because it's a literal um it's a it's a literal sort of pressing of that exact moment into Whereas I because of the amount of digitalization the amount
それは実際、そんなに遠くない。あの瞬間を、文字どおりプレスしている。一方、デジタル化の量のせいで、
of kind of like And then you're you know, and then you're listening to it in this way. You are actually very disconnected from it.
それから、こういう聴き方をすることになる。実際、とても切り離されている。
The The I think the future just looks bleak for for like recorded music, but it actually looks very bright for live music. I'm obsessed with this album.
録音された音楽の未来は暗いけれど、ライブの未来はとても明るいと思う。このアルバムに取り憑かれている。
Like I it is my favorite album I've ever made. I know every artist says that, but I think this is You can stand on that. It's my favorite album you've ever made.
今まで作ったなかで、いちばん好きだ。アーティストはみんなそう言うけれど、これは胸を張って言える。君が作った、いちばん好きなアルバムだ。
To me this is this is coloring anything, too.
僕にとって、これは『Coloring Anything』でもある。
Mhm. But an evolved and concise version. Mhm.
うん。でも、進化して、凝縮された版だ。
And I think it's the strongest possible foot I could have put forward. But my connection with an audience happens in the room. And it's why Vault is so special.
出せるなかで、いちばん強い第一歩だと思う。でも、聴く人とのつながりは、その部屋で起きる。だからVaultは特別なんだ。
It's why my gigs are so special. It's why I get up in the morning to to really do, you know, like to to make music is it's the ultimate destination for it is in front of you.
ライブが特別な理由だ。朝起きて音楽を作る理由は、その最終的な行き先が、君の目の前にあることだ。
Mhm. And I can do that with confidence because I spent 25 years doing it.
うん。25年やってきたから、自信を持ってそれができる。
What I think this album is going to really really um make very clear and evident to people, now that you are aware of it
このアルバムが、今それに気づいた人たちに、とてもはっきり示すと思うのは、
is that um even with the most minimal of accompaniment, um you uh can hold our attention in the most special way. This is a real compliment, like genuine compliment.
最小限の伴奏でも、特別な形で僕たちの注意をつかんで離さない、ということだ。これは本物の褒め言葉だ。
Like you've now found this relationship with your writing and your music. You are just like I know how to take you there now. You know what I mean?
書くことと音楽との関係を、今見つけた。どう連れていけばいいか、わかっている。わかるでしょ。
Yeah. I'm not just going to sing the song, like I'm going to hold it. And it's And that that's like Buckley That's like, "Oh he was somewhere else.
うん。ただ歌うだけではなく、それを抱えていられる。バックリーみたいだ。「彼は、どこか別の場所にいた。
I saw him live, he was somewhere else."
ライブで見た。別の場所にいた」。
Absolutely right. And And they said about Mahalia Jackson that when Mahalia was performing, she was performing to God.
まったくそのとおりだ。マヘリア・ジャクソンについて、彼女が歌うとき、神に向かって歌っていたと言われた。
Mhm. Mhm. And the audience were watching her.
うん。聴衆は、彼女を見ていた。
We're watching that conversation. Mhm. She wasn't necessarily performing to them.
その会話を見ていた。必ずしも、彼らに向かって演じていたわけではない。
Mhm. Um I I love that. would say that you know, every every performer is different. Some people have you know, it's almost like a Venn diagram, you know, some people have performing more to the audience and and less.
うん。それが好きだ。パフォーマーはみんな違う。ベン図みたいに、聴衆へ向ける割合が多い人も、少ない人もいる。
So. Um I don't know where I sit on that personally, but I know that like my you know, when I'm on stage, yeah, I'm I'm I'm really just sort of lost in the frequencies.
自分がどこにいるかは、個人的にはわからない。でもステージにいるとき、本当に周波数の中に迷い込んでいる。
I'm not really sort of particularly thinking about how I'm I connect in that way.
その意味で、どうつながるかを、特に考えていない。
Mhm. You know? Mhm. And ideally I'm helping people connect with themselves more than with me. Um and I think that's what my my music generally is. Um Very much so.
うん。理想としては、僕とより、自分自身とつながる手助けをしたい。僕の音楽は、だいたいそういうものだと思う。とてもそうだ。
I think that's why people are also drawn to you as such a as as a collaborator and want you to touch their music so much is because you know
人が君をコラボレーターとして引き寄せ、自分の音楽に触れてほしいと思うのは、
you are in service to some experience really at the end of the day that belongs to everybody.
結局のところ、みんなのものになる体験に仕えているからだ。
I mean I always think musicians get the best side of the trade because you get to learn the most and you get to have the experience of creating and releasing something, but
ミュージシャンは、取引のいちばんいい側をもらっていると思う。いちばん学べて、作って出す経験ができる。でも、
we do get something really wonderful out of it if we allow ourselves to to to lean into it. You know, and that's certainly the case with this record cuz you are somewhere else on this.
身を任せれば、僕たちも本当に素晴らしいものを受け取る。このレコードはまさにそれで、君は別の場所にいる。
It's like you have absolutely taken off any of the self-imposed barriers or restrictions you may have had toward devastating us and decided, you know what?
僕たちを打ちのめすことに対して、自分で課していた壁や制限を完全に外して、「これがそれだ」と決めたみたいだ。
This is what it is. Yeah. These are trying times and this album will reflect that in the most raw and real way possible.
これがそれだ。うん。今は厳しい時代で、このアルバムはそれを、できるかぎり生々しく、本物の形で映す。
Yes, trying times is is also the most kind of um like it's the biggest understatement of where we're at possible and and that's kind of that comes within English sort of sarcasm to
そう。『Trying Times』は、今いる場所に対する、最大の控えめな言い方でもある。そこにはイギリス英語の皮肉も入っていて、
it as well. You know, in the way of like, you know, the absolute worst thing can be happening and and it in England you go trying times.
最悪のことが起きていても、イギリスでは「trying timesだね」と言う。
Yeah, let's keep it light, mate. Yeah. Let's keep it light.
うん、軽くいこうぜ。うん。軽くいこう。
And you just get on with it. It's what my friend does all the time. He'll take us into like the depths of the darkest, doomy-est conversation pit.
そして、ただ続ける。友達がいつもそうする。いちばん暗くて、陰鬱な会話の穴へ連れていく。
And just when we're literally about to like go and tuck ourselves away behind closed doors and not come up for 24 hours, he just go Anyway, keep it light, mate.
扉の向こうに引っ込んで、24時間出たくなくなる直前に、「とにかく、軽くいこうぜ」と言う。
Keep it light. Keep it light. Keep it light. He was just the same thing. Keep it light.
軽く、軽く、軽く。彼も同じことを言っていた。軽くいこう。
Yeah. It's like, oh, yeah. Oh, yeah, Yeah, yeah.
うん。ああ、そうだね。
I don't feel any responsibility to keep it light, but I think he's fun That's a funny thing to say.
軽くいる責任は感じない。でも、彼がそう言うのは面白い。
Obviously. No. Um Oh, man, I'm so um glad to see you. I'm so happy. I I I didn't know whether you were going to make another album, per se
もちろん。いや。ああ、会えて本当に嬉しい。すごく嬉しい。またアルバムを作るのかどうか、わからなかった。
or you were just going to dabble in Vogue for the rest of your life and just keep it keep keep it light.
それとも残りの人生は、ヴォーグで遊びながら、ただ軽くい続けるのか、と。
Keep tasting my mates. Oh, yeah. Give me your actual phone number.
仲間に連絡し続ける。ああ。本当の電話番号をくれ。